AISHWARYA KALBURGI

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

		8073592311	
	\boxtimes	aishwaryakalburgi990@gmail.com	
		5th cross Bhagyanagar Belgaum 560009	
TECHNOLOGIES • Python			
	SPAHan IAMMySGIT	ARK ds-on AWS Services:DynamoDB, S3, AWS Glue, l, Lambda,Redshift DB,Appsync,CDK GQL and NoSQL	
	ObjeELK	in a Structures and Algorithms ect-Oriented Programming (OOP) Stack (Elasticsearch, Logstash, Kibana) o technologies:REACT,FLASK	
EDUCATION			
	BACHELORS DEGREE		
	B.E – B V Bhoomaraddi College Of		
	Engi	Engineering & Technology	
	2013-2017		
,	datab	ed a management system for the college pase in the form of a GUI using JAVA and MySQL gned and implemented an online results system bllege	
,	in uni Work	ed on developing a hand gesture controlled gam ty 3D integrated with OpenCV ed on developing an Optimized face recognition m using Gabor filter and SVM classifier	
	.,	3	
	PRE-UNIVERSITY		
CHETAN PU-COLLEGE HUBLI			
	2011-2013		
LANGUAGES		NGUAGES	
	Englis	sh ———	
	Kann	ada 🕳 💮	
	Hindi		

CONTACT

PROFILE

As a seasoned Software Engineer with 5.9 years of experience in the Information Technology (IT) sector, I have cultivated a deep passion for crafting software solutions. My enthusiasm drives me to stay up-to date with the latest technologies and continuously enhance my skill set, enabling me to contribute effectively within collaborative team environments. I eagerly look forward to applying my expertise and passion to have a profound impact on customers.

WORK EXPERIENCE

CLOUD AND AUTOMATION ENGINEER

MICROFOCUS

2017-2021

- Led a project utilising the ELK stack to retrieve, process, and create visualizations in Kibana for Micro Focus Pre-sales data.
- Worked on developing banking use cases (securitization, demand draft), testing, and defect fixing for the Westpac Banking application.
- Streamlined the process of building a Linux-based infrastructure and integrated it with Vcenter, Server Automation, and Operations Bridge Manager(OBM) within the Operation Orchestration tool
- Automated the generation of Workday expense Report through RPA (Robotic Process Automation)and UFT.
- Experience in working with REST APIs
- Contributed to ChatBot Development for Sungard customer
- Setting deeper log levels and troubleshooting 00 logs for issues
- · Worked on Netsuite APIs for P2P processing
- Automated the VM resource Utilisation summary generation in a excel worksheet with Python scripting
- Worked on building functionality & APIs to establish E-bonding between two incident management applications
- Enhanced workflow efficiency through automation. Tracked path usage within
 workflows to decide on path retention. Used Operations Orchestration for
 automation and integrated with Business Value Dashboard for clear performance
 insights.
- Automated the generation of daily status report sent to the Westpac banking client containing a snapshot of the application's performance and activities for that day, including details about successful transactions, errors encountered, metrics and highlighted spikes
- Developed utilities for basic Elastic Search CRUD operations in OO tool

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

2021-2022

PRODAPT

- Developed a dynamic SNMP query utility in Python using argparse and PySNMP libraries, enabling retrieval of specific information from remote devices for network management. Transformed it into a standalone application using PyInstaller for easy distribution
- Replaced the file-based approach with an API-based approach when directing information to ESP(Event Stream Processing), a component of Assure1, for data handling
- Exposure to concepts such as the Go programming language and Microservices, as well as technologies like Assure1

AISHWARYA KALBURGI

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

WORK EXPERIENCE

SUPPORT ENGINEER LEVEL 2

AMAZON

2022-present

Amazon Academy

- Implemented functionality and provided a user interface to clone content packs, establish bidirectional
 mappings of multiple offering IDs with content packs, facilitate the removal of offering IDs from
 content packs, and viewing offering IDs and content pack associations. This resulted in substantial
 reductions in manual workload for the content team, reducing a day long task ,with zero manual errors.
 Leveraged multiprocessing concepts for efficient bulk mapping and integrated with DynamoDB and
 ElasticSearch to retrieve offering ID data. Technology utilised: Flask.
- Implemented validations on daily digest (tip of the day) fields to eliminate delivery of blank/incorrect
 content for a specific day to the students using Java and Bash scripting. Also came up with a
 mechanism to update the Daily digest bundle.
- Automated solution to validate availability of all artifacts (DPP, Classnotes, watch recordings) for each session in the Live Lectures component of AA and notify teachers via email, as well as ensuring accuracy of content pack mapping. Technologies: Flask, S3, AppConfig, IAM.

Kindle accounting and royalty

- Worked on taking care of accounting launches and tech debts for Ebooks and Kindle Unlimited Business
- Automated the generation of Accounting Rollforward report for the Kindle Unlimited business utilising Datanet and Spark technologies. Received stakeholder appreciation for aligning with one of Amazon's leadership principles
- Developed a a new reporting solution to automate the generation of Accounting Aging report for Kindle
 unlimited subscriptions leveraging AWS services including AWS Glue, Lambda, Redshift database and
 AWS CDK. Using pyspark to transform and process the data and Kotlin to develop the new reporting
 solution
- Addressed a significant financial impact of approximately one \$1MM resulting from unbooked transactions in the accounting ledger,falling under a specific bucket of non-payment. Formulated rules and use cases within Axon to efficiently process those accounting events originating from upstream sources
- Performed redrives for reducing unbooked impact
- Experinced in ticket handling including sev 2 tickets and engaged in on-call responsibilities. Worked on resolving risks and weblab removal